Hey, this is Brian from Fullstack Egg.
When we set up paperless,
we use something called Docker,
and I'm going to tell you a little bit about it.
You can think of Docker like a collection of shipping containers that all have different things inside,
but because they are all inside of that same container,
it makes it really easy to manage,
and Docker does the same thing for software.
Instead of installing a program and hoping it works on your computer,
everything the program needs gets packed into a container.
So when you run that container, it just works,
and it doesn't matter if you're running it on your desktop computer
or on a VPS in the cloud, it always works the same.
So this is Docker desktop on my Mac,
and these are the containers running paperless right now on my computer.
There's a few of them working together, one for the database,
one for paperless itself,
and one for the search add-on that we built.
And here I'll show you them running in the terminal as well.
Each one is running in its own little box,
keeping things clean and separate.
And while this all might seem complicated,
you really don't have to be a programmer to set this up.
Docker handles all the complicated parts.
You basically say, "Run this,"
and it pulls everything down and starts it up.
And if something breaks, you throw away the container and start fresh.
Your data is stored separately, so nothing gets lost.
So that's Docker in a nutshell.
It packages software, so it runs the same everywhere,
and you don't have to worry about installing all these dependencies
and breaking things.
And for the paperless install videos,
you'll see that our setup script handles all the Docker stuff for you,
automatically, so you really don't have to worry about it.
And that's it for now.
Thanks again for watching.